{
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "Which is the most popular JavaScript framework?",
      "options": ["Angular", "React", "Svelte", "Vue"],
      "correctOption": 1,
      "points": 10,
      "language": "en"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which company invented React?",
      "options": ["Google", "Apple", "Netflix", "Facebook"],
      "correctOption": 3,
      "points": 10,
      "language": "en"
    },
    {
      "question": "What's the fundamental building block of React apps?",
      "options": ["Components", "Blocks", "Elements", "Effects"],
      "correctOption": 0,
      "points": 10,
      "language": "en"
    },
    {
      "question": "What's the name of the syntax we use to describe the UI in React components?",
      "options": ["FBJ", "Babel", "JSX", "ES2015"],
      "correctOption": 2,
      "points": 10,
      "language": "en"
    },
    {
      "question": "How does data flow naturally in React apps?",
      "options": [
        "From parents to children",
        "From children to parents",
        "Both ways",
        "The developers decides"
      ],
      "correctOption": 0,
      "points": 10,
      "language": "en"
    },
    {
      "question": "How to pass data into a child component?",
      "options": ["State", "Props", "PropTypes", "Parameters"],
      "correctOption": 1,
      "points": 10,
      "language": "en"
    },
    {
      "question": "When to use derived state?",
      "options": [
        "Whenever the state should not trigger a re-render",
        "Whenever the state can be synchronized with an effect",
        "Whenever the state should be accessible to all components",
        "Whenever the state can be computed from another state variable"
      ],
      "correctOption": 3,
      "points": 30,
      "language": "en"
    },
    {
      "question": "What triggers a UI re-render in React?",
      "options": [
        "Running an effect",
        "Passing props",
        "Updating state",
        "Adding event listeners to DOM elements"
      ],
      "correctOption": 2,
      "points": 20,
      "language": "en"
    },
    {
      "question": "When do we directly \"touch\" the DOM in React?",
      "options": [
        "When we need to listen to an event",
        "When we need to change the UI",
        "When we need to add styles",
        "Almost never"
      ],
      "correctOption": 3,
      "points": 20,
      "language": "en"
    },
    {
      "question": "In what situation do we use a callback to update state?",
      "options": [
        "When updating the state will be slow",
        "When the updated state is very data-intensive",
        "When the state update should happen faster",
        "When the new state depends on the previous state"
      ],
      "correctOption": 3,
      "points": 30,
      "language": "en"
    },
    {
      "question": "If we pass a function to useState, when will that function be called?",
      "options": [
        "On each re-render",
        "Each time we update the state",
        "Only on the initial render",
        "The first time we update the state"
      ],
      "correctOption": 2,
      "points": 30,
      "language": "en"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which hook to use for an API request on the component's initial render?",
      "options": ["useState", "useEffect", "useRef", "useReducer"],
      "correctOption": 1,
      "points": 10,
      "language": "en"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which variables should go into the useEffect dependency array?",
      "options": [
        "Usually none",
        "All our state variables",
        "All state and props referenced in the effect",
        "All variables needed for clean up"
      ],
      "correctOption": 2,
      "points": 30,
      "language": "en"
    },
    {
      "question": "An effect will always run on the initial render.",
      "options": [
        "True",
        "It depends on the dependency array",
        "False",
        "In depends on the code in the effect"
      ],
      "correctOption": 0,
      "points": 30,
      "language": "en"
    },
    {
      "question": "When will an effect run if it doesn't have a dependency array?",
      "options": [
        "Only when the component mounts",
        "Only when the component unmounts",
        "The first time the component re-renders",
        "Each time the component is re-rendered"
      ],
      "correctOption": 3,
      "points": 20,
      "language": "en"
    },
    {
      "question": "कौन सा जावास्क्रिप्ट फ्रेमवर्क सबसे लोकप्रिय है?",
      "options": ["एंगुलर", "रिएक्ट", "स्वेल्ट", "व्यू"],
      "correctOption": 1,
      "points": 10,
      "language": "hn"
    },
    {
      "question": "रिएक्ट का आविष्कार किस कंपनी ने किया था?",
      "options": ["गूगल", "एप्पल", "नेटफ्लिक्स", "फेसबुक"],
      "correctOption": 3,
      "points": 10,
      "language": "hn"
    },
    {
      "question": "रिएक्ट एप्लिकेशन के लिए मौलिक निर्माण इकाई क्या है?",
      "options": ["कंपोनेंट्स", "ब्लॉक्स", "एलीमेंट्स", "एफेक्ट्स"],
      "correctOption": 0,
      "points": 10,
      "language": "hn"
    },
    {
      "question": "रिएक्ट कंपोनेंट्स में UI को वर्णन करने के लिए हम कौन-सा सिंटैक्स उपयोग करते हैं?",
      "options": ["एफबीजे", "बेबेल", "जेएसएक्स", "ईएस 2015"],
      "correctOption": 2,
      "points": 10,
      "language": "hn"
    },
    {
      "question": "किसने जावास्क्रिप्ट नेत्रित्विक फ्रेमवर्क 'एंगुलर' का विकास किया?",
      "options": ["गूगल", "फेसबुक", "माइक्रोसॉफ्ट", "एप्पल"],
      "correctOption": 0,
      "points": 10,
      "language": "hn"
    },
    {
      "question": "रिएक्ट हुक्स का उपयोग क्यों किया जाता है?",
      "options": [
        "आप कंपोनेंट स्थानीय स्थिति को प्रबंधित कर सकते हैं",
        "आप कंपोनेंट के जीवन चक्र को प्रबंधित कर सकते हैं",
        "आप कंपोनेंट के नवीनतम स्थिति को अद्यतित कर सकते हैं",
        "सभी उपरोक्त"
      ],
      "correctOption": 3,
      "points": 10,
      "language": "hn"
    },
    {
      "question": "किस फंक्शनल प्रोग्रामिंग भाषा का एक पर्चल आवृत्ति है?",
      "options": ["जावास्क्रिप्ट", "पायथन", "हैस्केल", "रुबी"],
      "correctOption": 2,
      "points": 10,
      "language": "hn"
    },
    {
      "question": "विकल्प में से कौन-सा 'वर्गो' शैली का एक फ्रेमवर्क है?",
      "options": ["बूटस्ट्रैप", "मेटीर", "फाउंडेशन", "आप म्यूआई"],
      "correctOption": 1,
      "points": 10,
      "language": "hn"
    },
    {
      "question": "रिएक्ट नेटिव किस लैंग्वेज पर आधारित है?",
      "options": ["जावास्क्रिप्ट", "रिएक्ट", "जावा", "कोटलिन"],
      "correctOption": 0,
      "points": 10,
      "language": "hn"
    },
    {
      "question": "निम्नलिखित में से एक भी हो सकता है?",
      "options": ["स्टेट", "प्रोप्स", "रिफ्लेक्शन", "प्रोमिसेज"],
      "correctOption": 3,
      "points": 10,
      "language": "hn"
    }
  ]
}
